College presidents are not the first people who come to mind
رؤساء الجامعات ليسوا أول الناس الذين يأتون للذهن
when the subject is the uses of the creative imagination.
عندما يكون الموضوع هو من الخيال الخلاق.
So I thought I'd start by telling you how I got here.
أظن إنني في البداية سأخبركم عن كيف وصلت هنا.
The story begins in the late '90s.
تبدأ القصة في أواخر التسعينات.
I was invited to meet with leading educators
وقد دعيت للإجتماع مع كبار رجال التعليم
from the newly free Eastern Europe and Russia.
من أوروبا الشرقية وروسيا الحرة حديثا.
They were trying to figure out how to rebuild their universities.
وكانوا يحاولون معرفة كيفية إعادة بناء جامعاتهم.
Since education under the Soviet Union
ونظرا لأن التعليم في ظل الاتحاد السوفياتي
was essentially propaganda
هي دعاية في جوهرها
serving the purposes of a state ideology,
تخدم أغراض الدولة الأيديولوجية
they appreciated that it would take wholesale transformations
وأعربوا عن تقديرهم بأنهم الأمر سيأخذون التحولات بالجملة
if they were to provide an education
إذا كانت لتوفير التعليم
worthy of free men and women.
للجدير من الرجال والنساء.
Given this rare opportunity
ونظرا لهذه الفرصة النادرة
to start fresh,
لبداية جديدة،
they chose liberal arts
اختاروا الفنون الحرة
as the most compelling model
كالنموذج الأكثر إلحاحا
because of its historic commitment
بسبب الإتزام التاريخي
to furthering its students' broadest intellectual,
لتعزيز الطالب على أوسع النطق الفكرية
and deepest ethical potential.
وأعمق الأخلاق المحتملة.
Having made that decision
وقد اتخذ هذا القرار
they came to the United States,
لقد جاءوا إلى الولايات المتحدة،
home of liberal arts education,
مكان تعليم الفنون الليبرالية
to talk with some of us
للتحدث مع البعض منا
most closely identified
التعرف عن قرب
with that kind of education.
مع هذا النوع من التعليم.
They spoke with a passion, an urgency,
وتحدثوا بالعاطفة، وباستعجال،
an intellectual conviction
بقناعة فكرية
that, for me, was a voice I had not heard in decades,
هذا بالنسبة لي كان صوت لم أسمعه منذ قرون،
a dream long forgotten.
حلم طويل قد نسيته.
For, in truth, we had moved light years
في الحقيقة انتقلنا لسنوات النور
from the passions that animated them.
من العواطف التي تُنشي الحياة
But for me, unlike them,
ولكن بالنسبة لي، عكسهم،
in my world, the slate was not clean,
في عالمي، كانت اللائحة غير نظيفة.
and what was written on it was not encouraging.
وما مكتوب عليها لم يكن مشجعا.
In truth, liberal arts education
في الحقيقة، تعليم الفنون الليبرالية
no longer exists --
لم يعد موجودا،
at least genuine liberal arts education -- in this country.
على الأقل ليبرالية حقيقية تعليم الفنون، في هذا البلد.
We have professionalized liberal arts to the point
ولدينا إلى النقطة المهنية للفنون الليبرالية
where they no longer provide the breadth of application
حيث لم تعد توفر اتساعاً لنطاق التطبيق
and the enhanced capacity for civic engagement
وتعزيز القدرة على المشاركة المدنية
that is their signature.
هذا هو توقيعهم.
Over the past century
خلال القرن الماضي
the expert has dethroned the educated generalist
وقد خلع الخبراء اختصاصي التعليم،
to become the sole model
ليصبح النموذج الوحيد
of intellectual accomplishment. (Applause)
للإنجاز الفكري.
Expertise has for sure had its moments.
الخبرة وبالتأكيد كانت في أوجها في بعض الاحيان
But the price of its dominance is enormous.
لكن ثمن هيمنتها هائلة.
Subject matters are broken up
يتم تقسيم الموضوعات الهامة
into smaller and smaller pieces,
إلى قطع أصغر وأصغر،
with increasing emphasis on the technical and the obscure.
مع زيادة التركيز على التقنية والحجب.
We have even managed to make the study of literature arcane.
فقد تمكنا من جعل دراسة الأدب غامضة.
You may think you know what is going on
قد تعتقد أنك تعرف ما يجري
in that Jane Austen novel --
في ذلك رواية جين أوستن.
that is, until your first encounter
وهذا هو، حتى تصادف
with postmodern deconstructionism.
ديكونستركشنلزم مع ما بعد الحداثة.
The progression of today's college student
تطور الطالب الجامعي اليوم
is to jettison every interest except one.
هو التخلي عن كل مصلحة باستثناء شيء واحد.
And within that one, to continually narrow the focus,
وضمن ذلك الواحد، بمواصلة تضييق التركيز.
learning more and more about less and less;
تعلم أكثر وأكثر عن أشياء أقل وأقل.
this, despite the evidence all around us
هذا، على الرغم من الأدلة في كل مكان حولنا
of the interconnectedness of things.
تشير الى الترابط بين الأشياء.
Lest you think I exaggerate,
حتى لا تظن أنني أبالغ،
here are the beginnings of the A-B-Cs of anthropology.
وهنا بدايات خدمات الأنثروبولوجيا .
As one moves up the ladder,
باعتبارها كواحد يصعد السلم،
values other than technical competence
بخلاف كفاءة تقنية القيم
are viewed with increasing suspicion.
وينظر مع تزايد الشكوك.
Questions such as,
أسئلة مثل
"What kind of a world are we making?
أي نوع من العالم نحن نصنع ؟
What kind of a world should we be making?
أي نوع من العالم نحن يجب أن نبني ؟
What kind of a world can we be making?"
أي نوع من العالم نستطيع أن نعمل؟
are treated with more and more skepticism,
يتم التعامل مع المزيد والمزيد من الشكوك
and move off the table.
والانتقال من على الطاولة.
In so doing, the guardians of secular democracy
وبذلك، حراس الديمقراطية العلمانية
in effect yield the connection
في الواقع يعيدون الاتصال
between education and values
بين التعليم والقيم
to fundamentalists,
إلى الأصوليين.
who, you can be sure,
من ؟ ، ، يمكنك أن تتأكد،
have no compunctions about using education
لا يندمون حول استخدام التعليم
to further their values:
لتوسيع قيمهم،
the absolutes of a theocracy.
للمطلقات من دولة ثيوقراطية.
Meanwhile, the values and voices of democracy are silent.
وفي الوقت نفسه، القيم الديمقراطية للأصوات الصامتة.
Either we have lost touch with those values
إما فقدنا الاتصال مع تلك القيم،
or, no better,
أو أفضل حالا،
believe they need not
صدقنا بأننا لا نحتاجها
or cannot be taught.
أو لا يمكن تعليمها.
This aversion to social values
هذا النفور من القيم الاجتماعية
may seem at odds with the explosion
قد يبدو على خلاف مع انفجار
of community service programs.
برامج خدمة المجتمع.
But despite the attention paid to these efforts,
لكن على الرغم من الاهتمام لهذه الجهود
they remain emphatically extracurricular.
تظل اللامنهجية بشكل قاطع.
In effect, civic-mindedness is treated
في الواقع، هو تعامل الأفق المدنية
as outside the realm of what purports to be
وخارج نطاق ما يهدف إلى ان يكون
serious thinking and adult purposes.
جدية التفكير وأغراض الكبار.
Simply put, when the impulse is to change the world,
ببساطة، عندما يكون الدافع هو لتغيير العالم
the academy is more likely to engender
فالتعليم الأكاديمي من المرجح أن يولد ذلك
a learned helplessness
فتكون قد علمت العجز
than to create a sense of empowerment.
بدلا من خلق شعور من التمكين.
This brew -- oversimplification of civic engagement,
هذا الكوكتيل هو عبارة عن ، التبسيط المشاركة المدنية،
idealization of the expert,
تمجيد الخبير،
fragmentation of knowledge,
تجزئة المعرفة،
emphasis on technical mastery,
التركيز على إتقان التقنية،
neutrality as a condition of academic integrity --
الحياد كشرط من النزاهة الأكاديمية،
is toxic when it comes to pursuing the vital connections
سمية عندما يتعلق الأمر بمواصلة الاتصالات الحيوية
between education and the public good,
بين التعليم والصالح العام،
between intellectual integrity
بين النزاهة الفكرية
and human freedom,
وحرية الإنسان.
which were at the heart --
التي كانت في قلب
(Applause) -- of the challenge posed to and by
التحدي الذي استعرضه
my European colleagues.
زملائي الأوروبين
When the astronomical distance
هو عندما تكون المسافة الفلكية
between the realities of the academy
بين واقع الأكاديمية
and the visionary intensity of this challenge
وكثافة الحكيمة لهذا التحدي
were more than enough, I can assure you,
كبيرة جداً ..أؤكد لكم
to give one pause,
انه حان الوقت لإعطاء وقفة واحدة،
what was happening outside higher education
ماذا كان يحدث خارج التعليم العالي
made backing off unthinkable.
أدلى التراجع بأنه غير وارد.
Whether it was threats to the environment,
سواء كانت الأخطار التي تهدد البيئة،
inequities in the distribution of wealth,
تتمثل في عدم المساواة في توزيع الثروة،
lack of a sane policy or a sustainable policy
عدم وجود سياسة حكيمة أو سياسة مستدامة
with respect to the continuing uses of energy,
او فيما يتعلق بإستخدامات مستمرة من الطاقة.
we were in desperate straits.
كنا في وضع حرج.
And that was only the beginning.
وكان ذلك مجرد بداية.
The corrupting of our political life
وإفساد حياتنا السياسية
had become a living nightmare;
أصبحت كابوس.
nothing was exempt --
وليس استثناء.
separation of powers, civil liberties,
الفصل بين السلطات، والحريات المدنية،
the rule of law,
سيادة القانون،
the relationship of church and state.
العلاقة بين الكنيسة والدولة.
Accompanied by a squandering
مصحوبة بالتبذير
of the nation's material wealth
من الثروة المادية في البلاد
that defied credulity.
هذا يتحدى السذاجة.
A harrowing predilection for the uses of force
ميل مروع لاستخدامات القوة
had become commonplace,
قد يصبح أمرا مألوفا.
with an equal distaste
على قدم المساواة مع نفور
for the alternative forms of influence.
لأشكال بديلة من النفوذ.
At the same time, all of our firepower was impotent
وفي الوقت نفسه، كانت كل قوى النيران عاجزة لدينا
when it came to halting or even stemming
عندما جاء لوقف أو حتى الناشئة
the slaughter in Rwanda, Darfur, Myanmar.
المذبحة في رواندا ودارفور وميانمار.
Our public education, once a model for the world,
لدينا التعليم العام، ومرة ​​واحدة في نموذجا للعالم،
has become most noteworthy
أصبح أبرز
for its failures.
لإخفاقها.
Mastery of basic skills and a bare minimum of cultural literacy
إتقان المهارات الأساسية والحد الادنى من محو الأمية الثقافية
eludes vast numbers of our students.
يتملص أعداد كبيرة من طلابنا.
Despite having a research establishment
على الرغم من وجود مؤسسة للبحوث
that is the envy of the world,
وهذا هو موضع حسد العالم،
more than half of the American public
أكثر من نصف الشعب الأميركي
don't believe in evolution.
لا يؤمن بالتطور.
And don't press your luck
لا تضع حظك
about how much those who do believe in it
عن مدى أولئك الذين لا يؤمنون به
actually understand it.
فهم في الواقع.
Incredibly, this nation,
بشكل لا يصدق لا يؤمنون به ، هذه الأمة،
with all its material, intellectual and spiritual resources,
مع كل الموارد المادية والفكرية والروحية،
seems utterly helpless
تبدو عاجزة تماما
to reverse the freefall in any of these areas.
على عكس السقوط في أي مجال من هذه المجالات.
Equally startling, from my point of view,
مذهلة على قدم المساواة من وجهة نظري
is the fact that no one
هو حقيقة أن لا أحد
was drawing any connections
كان يصنع الجسور
between what is happening to the body politic,
بين ما يحدث في الجسم السياسي،
and what is happening in our leading educational institutions.
وبين ما يحدث في مؤسساتنا التعليمية الرائدة.
We may be at the top of the list
قد نكون في أعلى قائمة
when it comes to influencing access to personal wealth.
عندما يتعلق الأمر بالتأثير في الحصول على الثروة الشخصية.
We are not even on the list
نحن لسنا حتى على قائمة
when it comes to our responsibility
عندما يتعلق الأمر بمسؤوليتنا
for the health of this democracy.
بالنسبة لصحة الديمقراطية هذه.
We are playing with fire.
نحن نلعب بالنار.
You can be sure Jefferson knew
يمكنك أن تكون متأكدا بما كان يعرفه جيفرسون
what he was talking about when he said,
عندما كان يتحدث:
"If a nation expects to be ignorant and free
واضاف "اذا ارادت الامة ان تكون جاهلة و حرة
in a state of civilization,
في دولة الحضارة،
it expects what never was,
فان توقعها هذا لن يتم
and never will be."
ولن تكون أبدا.
(Applause)
تصفيق
On a more personal note,
والملاحظة الشخصية لدي تقول
this betrayal of our principles,
هذه خيانة لمبادئنا،
our decency, our hope,
لدينا اللياقة والأمل،
made it impossible for me
التي جعلت من المستحيل بالنسبة لي
to avoid the question,
تجنب هذه المسألة،
"What will I say, years from now,
وماذا سأقول، وسنوات من الآن،
when people ask, 'Where were you?'"
عندما يسأل الناس، أين كنت؟
As president of a leading liberal arts college,
رئيسا لكلية الفنون الحرة الرائدة،
famous for its innovative history,
تشتهر بتاريخها المبتكر،
there were no excuses.
لم تكن هناك أعذار.
So the conversation began at Bennington.
لذلك بدأت في المحادثة في بينينجتون.
Knowing that if we were to regain
مع العلم أنه إذا كان لنا أن نستعيد
the integrity of liberal education,
سلامة التعليم الليبرالي،
it would take radical rethinking
أن الآمر سيستغرق إعادة تفكير جذري
of basic assumptions,
من الإفتراضات الأساسية،
beginning with our priorities.
بداية مع أولوياتنا.
Enhancing the public good becomes a primary objective.
تعزيز الصالح العام يصبح الهدف الأساسي.
The accomplishment of civic virtue
إنجاز الفضيلة المدنية
is tied to the uses of intellect and imagination
ويرتبط لإستخدامات الفكر والخيال
at their most challenging.
في إجتماعهم الأكثر تحديا.
Our ways of approaching agency and authority
لدينا طرق وكالة قرب والسلطة
turn inside out to reflect the reality
بدوره الداخل إلى الخارج لتعكس واقع
that no one has the answers
أن لا أحد لديه أجوبة
to the challenges facing citizens in this century,
للتحديات التي تواجه المواطنين في هذا القرن،
and everyone has the responsibility
والجميع يتحمل المسؤولية
for trying and participating in finding them.
للمحاولة، والمشاركة في العثور عليهم.
Bennington would continue to teach the arts and sciences
سوف تستمر بينينجتون بتعليم الفنون والعلوم
as areas of immersion that acknowledge differences
كما أن مناطق الغمر معترف بالخلافات
in personal and professional objectives.
في الأهداف الشخصية والمهنية.
But the balances redressed,
لكن أرصدة تداركته،
our shared purposes assume an equal
أغراضنا المشتركة تفترض على قدم المساواة
if not greater importance.
إذا لا أهمية كبيرة.
When the design emerged it was surprisingly simple and straightforward.
عندما ظهرت في تصميم بسيط وكان من المستغرب وضوحه.
The idea is to make the political-social challenges themselves --
والفكرة هي جعل التحديات السياسية والإجتماعية بأنفسهم،
from health and education
من الصحة والتعليم،
to the uses of force --
إلى استخدام القوة،
the organizers of the curriculum.
المنظمون من المنهج الدراسي.
They would assume the commanding role of traditional disciplines.
وتولوا دور قيادي من التخصصات التقليدية.
But structures designed to connect, rather than divide
لكن الهياكل مصممة للربط بدلا من الانقسام،
mutually dependent circles,
دوائر الاعتماد المتبادل،
rather than isolating triangles.
بدلا من عزل المثلثات.
And the point is not to treat these topics
والنقطة المهمة هي عدم التعامل مع هذه المواضيع
as topics of study,
مثل موضوعات الدراسة،
but as frameworks of action.
ولكن كما أطر العمل.
The challenge: to figure out what it will take
هذا التحدي، لمعرفة ما سوف يستغرق
to actually do something
أن تفعل شيئا في الواقع
that makes a significant and sustainable difference.
أن يحدث فرقا كبيرا ومستداما.
Contrary to widely held assumptions,
على عكس الافتراضات التي عقدت على نطاق واسع،
an emphasis on action provides a special urgency to thinking.
التركيز على عمل يوفر إلحاح خاص للتفكير.
The importance of coming to grips with values like justice,
على أهمية التوصل إلى السيطرة على قيم مثل العدالة،
equity, truth,
الإنصاف والحقيقة،
becomes increasingly evident
يصبح واضحا على نحو متزايد
as students discover that interest alone
كما اكتشف أن الطلاب المستفيدون الوحيدون
cannot tell them what they need to know
لا نستطيع أن نقول لهم ما يحتاجون إلى معرفته
when the issue is rethinking education,
عندما يكون الأمر على إعادة النظر في التعليم،
our approach to health,
نهجنا في الصحة،
or strategies for achieving
أو إستراتيجيات لتحقيق
an economics of equity.
إقتصاد يتمتع بالإنصاف.
The value of the past also comes alive;
قيمتة الماضية موجودة
it provides a lot of company.
وهو يوفر الكثير للشركة.
You are not the first to try to figure this out,
لم تكن أول محاولة لفهم هذا
just as you are unlikely to be the last.
تماما كما اعتقد من غير المرجح أن تكون الأخيرة.
Even more valuable,
حتى أكثر قيمة،
history provides a laboratory
التاريخ يوفر المختبر
in which we see played out
التي نراها تلعب خارجا
the actual, as well as the intended
الفعلي، فضلا عن القصد
consequences of ideas.
نتائج الأفكار.
In the language of my students,
في لغة طلابي،
"Deep thought matters
مسائل التفكير العميق
when you're contemplating what to do
عندما كنت تفكر في ما يجب القيام به
about things that matter."
حول مسألة الأشياء.
A new liberal arts that can support this
والفنون الليبرالية الجديدة التي يمكن أن تدعم هذا
action-oriented curriculum
منحى المناهج
has begun to emerge.
وقد بدأت في الظهور.
Rhetoric, the art of organizing the world of words
الخطابة، فن تنظيم العالم من الكلمات
to maximum effect.
إلى أكبر قدر من التأثير.
Design, the art of organizing the world of things.
التصميم، فن تنظيم العالم من الأشياء.
Mediation and improvisation
الوساطة والإرتجال
also assume a special place in this new pantheon.
تفترض أيضا مكانة خاصة في هذه الآلهة الجديدة.
Quantitative reasoning attains its proper position
التفكير الكمي يبلغ موقف السليم
at the heart of what it takes to manage change
في قلب ما يلزم لإدارة التغيير
where measurement is crucial.
حيث قياسه أمر بالغ الأهمية.
As is a capacity to discriminate
كما لديه القدرة على التمييز
systematically between what is at the core
منهجية بين ما هو في الصميم
and what is at the periphery.
وما هو في الهامش.
And when making connections is of the essence,
وعند إجراء الإتصالات هو جوهر المسألة،
the power of technology emerges with special intensity.
قوة التكنولوجيا تخرج مع الكثافة الخاصة.
But so does the importance of content.
ولكنه يفعل ذلك لأهمية المحتوى.
The more powerful our reach,
الأقوى في متناول أيدينا،
the more important the question "About what?"
والأهم من ذلك هو السؤال حول ماذا؟
When improvisation, resourcefulness, imagination are key,
عند الارتجال، الحيلة والخيال هي المفتاح،
artists, at long last,
الفنانين، في الماضي البعيد،
take their place at the table,
تأخذ مكانها على الطاولة،
when strategies of action are in the process of being designed.
استراتيجيات العمل هي في طور التصميم.
In this dramatically expanded ideal
في هذا التوسع المثالي بشكل كبير
of a liberal arts education
لتعليم الفنون الليبرالية
where the continuum of thought and action is its life's blood,
حيث استمرارية الفكر والعمل والحياة الحيوية
knowledge honed outside the academy
المعرفة وشحذ بعد الحياة الأكاديمية
becomes essential.
يصبح من الضروري.
Social activists, business leaders,
النشطاء الاجتماعيين، وقادة الأعمال،
lawyers, politicians, professionals
المحامين والسياسيين والمهنيين
will join the faculty as active and ongoing participants
وسوف ينضم إلى هيئة التدريس والمشاركين النشطين والمستمرين
in this wedding of liberal education to the advancement of the public good.
في هذا العرس من التعليم الليبرالي للنهوض الصالح العام.
Students, in turn, continuously move outside the classroom
الطلاب، وبدوره، نقل باستمرار خارج الفصول الدراسية
to engage the world directly.
للانخراط في العالم مباشرة.
And of course, this new wine
وبطبيعة الحال، هذا النبيذ جديد
needs new bottles
نحتاج لزجاجات جديدة
if we are to capture the liveliness and dynamism
إذا أردنا التقاط الحيوية والدينامية
of this idea.
من هذه الفكرة.
The most important discovery we made
أهم اكتشاف عملنا به
in our focus on public action
في تركيزنا على العمل العام
was to appreciate that the hard choices
وكان لنقدر أن الخيارات الصعبة
are not between good and evil,
ليس بين الخير والشر،
but between competing goods.
ولكن بين السلع المتنافسة.
This discovery is transforming.
هذا الاكتشاف هو تحويل.
It undercuts self-righteousness,
إنه يضعف الذات،
radically alters the tone and character of controversy,
يغير جذريا لهجة وطابع الجدل،
and enriches dramatically
ويثري بشكل كبير
the possibilities for finding common ground.
إمكانيات التوصل إلى أرضية مشتركة.
Ideology, zealotry,
الفكر، التعصب،
unsubstantiated opinions simply won't do.
آراء لا أساس لها ببساطة لن تفعل.
This is a political education, to be sure.
وهذا التثقيف السياسي للتأكد.
But it is a politics of principle,
وإنما هو سياسة من حيث المبدأ،
not of partisanship.
ليس من التحزب.
So the challenge for Bennington is to do it.
لذا فإن التحدي الذي يواجه بينينجتون هو أن نفعل ذلك.
On the cover of Bennington's 2008 holiday card
على غلاف بطاقة بينينجتون عطلة ٢٠٠٨
is the architect's sketch of a building
هو الرسم المعماري للمبنى
opening in 2010
فتح في ٢٠١٠
that is to be a center for the advancement
هذا هو لتكون مركزا للنهوض
of public action.
العمل العلني.
The center will embody and sustain this new educational commitment.
وسيقوم المركز بتجسيد هذا الالتزام والمحافظة التعليمية الجديدة.
Think of it as a kind of secular church.
كما أنها تفكر في نوع من الكنيسة العلمانية.
The words on the card describe what will happen inside.
عبارة عن بطاقة وصف ما سيحدث في الداخل.
We intend to turn the intellectual
ونحن نعتزم تحويل الفكرية
and imaginative power, passion and boldness
وسلطة الخيال، والعاطفة والجرأة
of our students, faculty and staff
من أعضاء هيئة التدريس والطلاب والموظفين
to developing strategies
وضع استراتيجيات
for acting on the critical challenges of our time.
ليتصرف على التحديات الخطيرة في عصرنا.
So we are doing our job.
لذلك نحن نقوم بواجبنا.
While these past weeks have been a time
في حين كانت هذه الأسابيع الماضية تأخذ وقتا
of national exhilaration in this country,
من الابتهاج الوطني في هذا البلد،
it would be tragic if you thought this meant
وسيكون مأساويا إذا كنت تعتقد أن هذا يعني
your job was done.
وقد تم عملك.
The glacial silence we have experienced
صمت الجليد عانينا
in the face of the shredding of the constitution,
في وجه التمزيق من الدستور،
the unraveling of our public institutions,
وانهيار مؤسساتنا العامة،
the deterioration of our infrastructure
تدهور البنية التحتية
is not limited to the universities.
لا يقتصر على الجامعات.
We the people
نحن الشعب
have become inured to our own irrelevance
أصبحوا معتادين على عدم الجدوى من منطقتنا
when it comes to doing anything significant
عندما يتعلق الأمر بالقيام بأي شيء كبير
about anything that matters
عن أي شيء مهم
concerning governance,
بشأن الحكم،
beyond waiting another four years.
بعد انتظار أربع سنوات أخرى.
We persist also
ونحن أيضا قائمين
in being sidelined by the idea of the expert
في تهميشه من فكرة الخبير
as the only one capable of coming up with answers,
بوصفها واحدة فقط قادرة على الخروج مع الإجابات.
despite the overwhelming evidence to the contrary.
على الرغم من أدلة دامغة على عكس ذلك.
The problem is there is no such thing
المشكلة هو عدم وجود شيء من هذا القبيل
as a viable democracy made up of experts,
بوصفها دولة ديمقراطية قابلة للحياة تتألف من خبراء،
zealots, politicians and spectators.
المتعصبين والسياسيين والمتفرجين.
(Applause)
تصفيق
People will continue and should continue
سوف يستمر الناس ويجب أن تستمر
to learn everything there is to know about something or other.
لمعرفة كل شيء هناك لمعرفة شيء أو غيرها.
We actually do it all the time.
نحن فعلا في كل وقت.
And there will be and should be
وسوف يكون هناك وينبغي أن يكون
those who spend a lifetime
الذين ينفقون العمر
pursuing a very highly defined area of inquiry.
تتبع منطقة محددة جدا جدا من التحقيق.
But this single-mindedness will not yield
ولكن هذا الذي وحيد بلا تفكير لم يسفر
the flexibilities of mind,
المرونة الذهنية،
the multiplicity of perspectives,
تعدد وجهات النظر،
the capacities for collaboration and innovation
قدرات للتعاون والابتكار
this country needs.
البلد يحتاجه.
That is where you come in.
هذا هو المكان الذي تأتي فيه.
What is certain is that the individual talent
ما هو مؤكد هو أن المواهب الفردية
exhibited in such abundance here,
عرضت في وفرة هذه هنا،
needs to turn its attention
بدوره يحتاج إلى اهتمامه
to that collaborative, messy, frustrating,
إلى أن التعاونية، والفوضى، والإحباط
contentious and impossible world
جدل ويستحيل العالم
of politics and public policy.
السياسة والسياسة العامة.
President Obama and his team
الرئيس أوباما وفريقه
simply cannot do it alone.
ببساطة لا يمكن ان تفعل ذلك وحدها.
If the question of where to start seems overwhelming
إذا كان السؤال من أين تبدأ يبدو ساحق
you are at the beginning, not the end of this adventure.
كنت في بداية وليس نهاية هذه المغامرة.
Being overwhelmed is the first step
طغيان هو الخطوة الأولى
if you are serious about trying to get at things that really matter,
إذا كنتم جادين في محاولة للحصول على الأشياء التي يهم حقا،
on a scale that makes a difference.
على نطاق والتي تحدث فرقا.
So what do you do when you feel overwhelmed?
لذا ماذا تفعل عندما تشعر أنك طغت؟
Well, you have two things.
حسنا، لديك شيئين.
You have a mind. And you have other people.
لديك عقل. وكان لديك أشخاص آخرين.
Start with those, and change the world.
نبدأ بها، وتغيير العالم.
(Applause)
تصفيق